Guide to the David Locke Webster Papers SC0131
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
David Locke Webster papers
1914-1970
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Webster, David Locke
SC0131
14.25 Linear Feet
Scope and Content
The papers of David Locke Webster document his career as a professor and physicist and include course material from physics classes taught at Stanford (1946-1954); notes and notebooks from his earlier teaching career at Harvard, Michigan and M.I.T.; correspondence and subject files on Army research projects; budget material for the Stanford physics department (1924-1943); reprints of articles; research data; photographs of apparatus used in experiments; and manuscripts.
Biographical Note
Born in Boston, November 6, 1888, David Locke Webster attended Harvard University, receiving his bachelor's in 1910 and his doctorate three years later, both in physics. While studying at Harvard, Webster also taught as an instructor in mathematics (1909-12) and as an assistant in physics (1911-14). After receiving his advanced degree, he held an instructorship in physics until 1917.
In the autumn of that year, Webster assumed the position of Assistant Professor of Physics at the University of Michigan. This appointment was short-lived, as the American entry into the First World War intervened and Webster was commissioned as a lieutenant in the Air Service of the Army. By October of 1918, he had been promoted to captain, the rank he would hold in the air reserves from Armistice until 1924. Webster returned to Michigan, but within the year accepted another offer of an assistant professorship, this one at Massachusetts Institute of Technology.
After a single year at M.I.T., Webster came to Stanford, where he had been offered full professorial status and the position of executive department head. He remained Professor of Physics at Stanford until 1954, when he retired. He functioned as department head until 1942, when he took an official leave of absence to serve in World War II. During the subsequent three years he held the posts of head Signal Service physicist, head physicist at large for the Ordnance Department, and chief Army physicist.
Webster married Anna Cutler Woodman in June, 1912, with whom he had two daughters (Nancy, Helen) and two sons (David Locke Jr., Cutler). In September of 1951, he married his second wife, Olive Durbin Ross. Webster's long-standing avocation was flying. He coordinated the civilian pilot training program at Stanford (1939-41) and co-authored two pilot training manuals.
Working with H.W. Farwell and E.R. Drew, Webster produced General Physics for Colleges in 1923. He was a member of the board of editors for the Review of Modern Physics from 1929 to 1948, and of the American Physics Teacher from 1933 to 1935. He also contributed to the Encyclopedia Brittanica.
Webster belonged to a number of professional societies, was elected to the National Academy of Sciences, American Physical Society, American Academy of Arts and Sciences, American Philosophical Society, and Phi Beta Kappa. He listed his religious preference as agnostic.
[Information obtained from Who's Who in America, Volume 32, 1962-63.]
Provenance
Gift of David Locke Webster 1974, 1976 and Dr. and Mrs. Sergius Bryer, 1979; and transfer from the Stanford University Dept. of Physics, 1987.
Access Restrictions
None.
World War, 1939-1945; Physics -- History.; Klystrons.; Webster, David Locke; Stanford University. Department of Physics; Webster, David Locke; United States.. Army.
- Papers, 1914-1964; Series A
  - Stanford University Course Materials, 1941-1954
    - Math 10-24, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Physics 23, Electricity, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Physics 23, Winter 1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Physics 23, Winter 1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Physics 35, Electricity with calculus. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Physics 37, Light and Sound, Winter 1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Physics 51, Plans and records. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Physics 51, Autumn 1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Physics 51, Quizzes., Autumn 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Physics 51, Lecture Notes., Autumn 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Physics 51, Lecture Notes., Autumn 1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Physics 51, Autumn, 1950, 1951, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Physics 51, Piston Inertia., Autumn 1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Physics 51, Autumn 1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Physics 51, Autumn 1951 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Physics 51, Quizzes., Autumn 1951 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Physics 51, Autumn 1952 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Physics 51, Autumn 1952 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Physics 51, Autumn 1952 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Physics 51, Extracurricular Information: Highbrow., Autumn 1952 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Physics 51, Mimeo Notes., Autumn 1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Physics 51, Mimeo Notes., Autumn 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Physics 51, Mimeo Notes., Autumn1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Physics 51, Apparatus for Sound., Autumn 1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Physics 51, Odd jobs, Lowbrow, Autumn 1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Physics 51, Lecture notes., Autumn 1953 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Physics 51, Lecture notes., Autumn 1953 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Physics 51, Mimeo notes, problems, quizzes, and final exam., Autumn 1953 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Physics 91, Lecture notes., Winter 1952 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Physics 91, Mimeo notes, desk copies of problems., Winter 1952 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Physics 91, Mimeo notes., Winter 1953 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Physics 91, Mimeo notes., Winter 1953 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Physics 91, Mimeo notes., Winter 1953 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Physics 91, Lecture notes., Winter and Spring 1953 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Physics 91, Lecture notes., Winter 1954 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Physics 91, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapter 1., Winter 1954 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Physics 91, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapter 2., Winter 1954 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Physics 91, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapter 3., Winter 1954 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Physics 91, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapter 4., Winter 1954 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Physics 91, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapter 5., Winter 1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Physics 91, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapter 6., Winter 1954 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Physics 91, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapter 7., Winter 1954 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Physics 91, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapter 8., Winter 1954 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Physics 91, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapter 9., Winter 1954 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Physics 93, Lectures 1-13., Spring 1952 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Physics 93, Lectures 14-28., Spring 1952 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Physics 93, Mimeo notes and desk copies of problems., Spring 1952 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Physics 93, Lecture notes., Spring 1953 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Physics 93, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapter 6., Spring 1953 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Physics 93, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapters 6-7., Spring 1953 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Physics 93, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapters 6-8., Spring 1953 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Physics 93, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapter 7., Spring 1953 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Physics 93, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapter 7, Single Pages., Spring 1953 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Physics 93, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapter 7, Pieces., Spring 1953 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Physics 93, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapter 7, Before Change of Plan., Spring 1953 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Physics 93, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapter 7, After Change of Plan., Spring 1953 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Physics 93, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapter 8., Spring 1953 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Physics 93, Mimeo notes to be used as book: Chapters 7-12., Spring 1954 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Physics 93, Lecture notes., Spring 1954 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Physics 94, and before., Spring 1952 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Physics 94, Reports., Spring 1952 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Physics 123, Lecture notes., Winter 1946 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Physics 123, Problems and final examination., Winter 1946 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Physics 221, Lecture notes I., Autumn 1946 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Physics 221, Lecture notes II, Autumn 1946 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Physics 221, Lecture notes I., Autumn 1947 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Physics 221, Lecture notes II, Autumn 1947 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Physics 221, Lecture notes I., Autumn 1948 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Physics 221, Lecture notes II, Autumn 1948 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Physics 221, Lecture notes I., Autumn 1949 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Physics 221, Lecture notes II, Autumn 1949 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Physics 221, Lecture notes I., Autumn 1950 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Physics 221, Lecture notes II, Autumn 1950 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Physics 221, 223, 225, Lecture notes, mimeo notes, desk copies of problems., Winter 1950-51 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Physics 223, Lecture notes I., Winter 1950 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Physics 223, Lecture notes II, Winter 1950 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Physics 223, Lecture notes I., Winter 1951 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Physics 223, Lecture notes II, Winter 1951 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Physics 225, Lecture notes I., Spring 1947 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Physics 225, Lecture notes II, Spring 1947 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Physics 225, Lecture notes I., Spring 1948 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Physics 225, Lecture notes II, Spring 1948 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Physics 225, Lecture notes I., Spring 1949 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Physics 225, Lecture notes II, Spring 1949 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Physics 225, Lecture notes I., Spring 1950 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Physics 225, Lecture notes II., Spring 1950 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Physics 225, Lecture notes I., Spring 1951 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Physics 225, Lecture notes II., Spring 1951 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Physics 247, Schiff's Course on Theory of Solids, Lecture notes., 1948 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Pre-Stanford Course Materials, 1914-1920
    - Harvard: Physics 9, Notes on Papers. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Harvard: Physics 10, Lecture notes. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Harvard: Physics 10 and Math 11 Problems, Physics 13 notes. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Harvard: Physics 13 notes. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Harvard: Physics 12b, X-ray course, Lecture notes, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Harvard: Physics 12b, X-ray course, Lecture notes, 1916-17 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Harvard: Physics 12b, X-ray course, Lecture notes, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Harvard: Physics C, Notes, 1913-14 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Harvard: Physics C, Notes, 1916-17 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Harvard: Notes and Calculations for Research on Optical Activity, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Harvard: Experiments on the Distribution of Ionizing Power in the Tungsten X-ray Spectrum, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Harvard: Data on Critical Potentials of L Series (with Clark), 1916-17 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Harvard: Notes for Talk on Rules Versus Imagination in Elementary Physics and Mathematics In Philadelphia, Pa., 21-Apr-17 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Michigan: Lecture notes on X-rays, Vol. I., 1917 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Michigan: Lecture notes on X-rays, Vol. II., 1917 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Michigan: Lecture notes on X-rays, Vol. III., 1917 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Michigan: Lecture notes on X-rays, Vol. IV., 1917 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Michigan: X-ray spectra, Wave length and theories, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Michigan - M.I.T.: Critical Potentia Phenomena in Light, through 1919. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - M.I.T.: Theory of X-ray emission, calculations on energy distribution with preliminary data, 1919 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - M.I.T.: Data on X-rays and tests of high tension, 1919-20 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Manuscript Materials and Research Data, 1961-1964
    - Typewritten manuscript of book on electrical principles (title uncertain), Chapters 1-6. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Typewritten manuscript of book on electrical principles (title uncertain), Chapters 13-18 [See also Course Material for Physics 91, Box 3.] (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Research Material: Quantum effects in chemical reactions. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Draft of Tsunamis at Small Islands, manuscript with notes (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Tsunamis: Abstract of August 1961; and 1961b. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Tsunamis: With Hankel; secondaries: Tech. Memo #69 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Tsunamis: Cox, Doak C., May 3-Aug 20, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Tsunamis: Hawaii, Aug 24-Sep ember 20, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Tsunamis: On slopes without islands, 1961c. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Tsunamis: On slopes around very small islands, 1961b & d. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Tsunamis: Cox, letters etcetera on underwater slopes with no islands, Oct 1961-Jan 1962 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Tsunamis: Basic Formulas, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Tsunamis: The Group that Debugged the Program, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Tsunamis: Cox, with small islands on tops of slopes, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Tsunamis: On slopes without any islands, ctd., 1962a. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Tsunamis: T. with q equals 1 etcetera, by Marchant computer. (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Tsunamis: Rough draft of part of report, Jun-63 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Tsunamis: Byrne Perry, Jun 1962-Feb 1964 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Tsunamis: Perry, Mss. of February 1964; Wong, et. al., 1964b. (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Tsunamis: Formulas/Programs/Data, Folder A. (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Tsunamis: Formulas/Programs/Data, Folder B. (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Tsunamis: Formulas/Programs/Data, Folder C. (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Tsunamis: Formulas/Programs/Data, Folder D. (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Tsunamis: Formulas/Programs/Data, Folder E. (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Tsunamis: Copies of Reports by Colleagues: Johnson, Norris, Cox, and Van Dorn. (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Proceedings of the Tenth Pacific Science Congress, Honolulu, Hawaii, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Research Memorabilia (Box 10)
    - Copy of Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, Volume III, No. 3, Containing an article by D.L. Webster and Harry Clark, The Intensities of X-Rays of the L Series, pp. 181-185., Mar-17
    - Assorted photographic prints, plates, and glass negatives showing various apparati used in experimentation.
    - Models of the Hawaiian Islands given to Webster and his wife Olive by Dr. James A. Fleming, 1961 (Box 11)
- Papers, 1917-1943; Series B
  - Correspondence, 1917-1921
    - DLW's army assignments; University of Michigan; personal correspondence., September - December 1917: (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - correspondence received while in the service: official Army memoranda and travel orders; personal correspondence from family and friends., January - May 1918: (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - same as above., June - September 1918: (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - October correspondence chiefly concerned with DLW's promotion to captain; November concerned with death of his brother Harrison, killed in action in France., October - December 1918: (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - January correspondence concerned with DLW's discharge from active duty; February 1921 relates to job offer (not taken) with the Engineering Division of the U.S. Air Services., January 1919; February 1921: (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Personal Subject Files, 1918-1936
    - War Diary, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Documents on flying status, flight logs and correspondence concerning DLW's aviation training., March - November 1918: (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Legal Documents, Military registration cards; I.D. card; insurance policy; leases., 1918 - 1919: (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Discharge papers, December 1918 - 1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Scope and Contents note
      (Actual discharge occurred January 15, 1919; subsequent correspondence is related to veteren's benefits)
  - Army Research Subject Files, 1917-1924
    - Magnet bomb, reports - Experiments on magnet bomb Experiments on magnet bomb #2 blueprints and graphs., 1917 Sep ember 4, 1917; Sep 14, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bomb trajectory after Duff, Sieg and Webster - Langley Field, 1918: blueprints. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Drift sights, reports, graphs, and correspondence concerning experiments., February 1918 - January 1919: (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Instruments for tests of DH 4: inventories of, and correspondence related to, instruments and supplies procured for DLW's scientific tests in the army. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Photographs: Bomb trajectory photos; Drift sights; airplane pictures. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Glass negative from photo by Nietz (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Blueprint of chain-of-command of Science and Research Division of the Army. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Reprints, Stanford University Dept. of Physics Records, and Miscellaneous Files, 1914-1970
    - Correspondence - Army Reserve Service, Oct 1921-Mar 1924 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Bibliography of reprints: list compiled covers articles from, May 1970, 1914-1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - REPRINTS (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - The effect of pressure on the absorption of light by bromine and chlorine and its theoretical significance, Sep-14
      - The theory of electromagnetic mass of the Parson magneton and other non spherical systems, June 1917
      - The scattering of alpha rays as evidence on the Parson magnetron hypothesis, Feb-18
      - The physics of flight, May 1920
      - Quantum emission phenomena - radiation, May 1920
      - The present conception of atomic structure, July 1921
      - A general survey of the present status of the atomic structure problem, July 1921
      - Note on the masses of stars, Jan-22
      - Surface currents in deep tidal waters, Aug-39
      - Perceptual disorientation during landing of airplane, Dec-40
      - Forces on ferromagnets through which electrons are moving, Dec-46
      - Masses of carriers in conductors, June 1951
    - Recommendations for promotion, candidates: E.R. Drew, F.J. Rogers, 1922 - 1923 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1924/25 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1925/26 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1926/27 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1927/28 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1928/29 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1929/30 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1930/31 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1931/32 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1932/33 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1933/34 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1934/35 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1935/36 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1936/37 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1937/38 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1938/39 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1939/40 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1940/41 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1941/42 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Physics Department Budgets, 1942/43 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Papers, circa 1928-1960; Series C
  - Bessel Etal. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Feroelectric Materials I (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Feroelectric Materials and Dr. A de Bretteville (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Gyromagnetic and Electron Inertia Effects (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lecture Apparatus: Electricity And Sound (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Relativity: Miscellaneous Notes and Papers (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Relativity and Parallel Wires in 1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Book: Ideas not used but perhaps useful in revision (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - For Ch.17 and 18: Odd Jobs and Background data (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - For 16: Background Data Etc. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - For 15: Background Data, Ideas, Etc. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Radiation Resistances (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - For Ch.14: Ideas and Data, Aside from those in other books and notes (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - For Ch. 13: Background Data, Notes on Maxwell, Etc. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - For Ch. 12: Background Data, Reprints, Etc. Hering's Trouser - Guard Expt. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Electrets (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Magnetostatics, Ring (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Physics of the Magnetosphere (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Relativity: pp. 221-3 Etc. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - For Ch. 5: Background Data, Calculations, Etc. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - For Ch. 4: Background Data, Etc. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - For Ch. 1: Background Data, Etc. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Relativity: Notes Used in Courses (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Book: Dwgs. & Photos - Made for EB but likely to be useful in book also (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Ventura School Astronomy Course, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Prints, Magnetic Field, For D.L. Webster (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Meteorite Craters, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Meteorite Craters, Barringer Et Al., 1931- (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Meteor Crater, 1930- (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Meteor Crater, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Meteor Crater, Earlier, 1928 & (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - X-Rays (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Flight Theory (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Meteor Crater, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Papers, 1918-1966; Series D
  - The Physics of Flight, article and notes, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and assorted papers, 1920-21 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    (includes R.L. Wilbur, E.A. Wilson, and H.N. Russell)
  - Correspondence re GE position, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with Pres. Wilbur and papers, 1926-30 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Pres. Wilbur and class roll books, 1931-32 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Pres. Wilbur and abstract for Salt Lake City meeting, 1932-34 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence with Pres. Wilbur and notes re Honor Code Panel, 1934-38 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Assorted correspondence and research contract, 1938-39 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Assorted correspondence, notes, articles, and other items, 1939-42 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Xray reprints, 1927-39 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Surface Currents in Deep Tidal Waters, and a later related paper, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dynamic Policy, Stanford and World War II, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Notes, correspondence, and papers re Klystron job, 1938-42 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Patent for production of high speed electrons, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Velocity Modulation Currents, 1942-43 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, notes, and articles re MAD, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Other War jobs after MAD (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - NDRC, Sec D3, Stanford research, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - High Flying: proposed job with Army, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Army pilot training, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Civil pilot training, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and notes re Klystron (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence re sabatical to NDRC (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence with Navy, Dec 1941-Feb 1942 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Non-personal correspondence, July 1942-45 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Army, record of consultant jobs, 1946-55 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bessel functions, etc. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Klystrons, post-war (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, notes, and diagrams re Klystron (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Bloch file, 1956, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with Varian Associates (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Densitometer records on horizons (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Optical horizon data (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence re optical horizons job (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Optical horizon project: data, reports, etc, 1950-51 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Cox and tsunamis, 1963-64 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Tsunamis/Brophy, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Tsunamis/Adams, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Tsunamis/Perry, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Tsunamis/Perry, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Tsunamis/Williams (Box 3, Folder 14)